<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R-Ladies Chicago on R-Ladies Chicago</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R-Ladies Chicago on R-Ladies Chicago</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Viz Study Group Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-09-10_dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-09-10_dataviz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Data Viz study group for their first meeting!  We&amp;rsquo;ll be exploring the grammar of graphics with R. There will also be an introduction to ggplot2. All are welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please email study group coordinator Ola [at] rladies dot org or join our &lt;strong&gt;#sg-dataviz&lt;/strong&gt; slack channel with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-chicago/events/254251305/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-chicago/events/254251305/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Blog Posts</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-16_blog_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-16_blog_info/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R-Ladies Chicago is excited to start this blog to showcase the perspectives of different members in the R-Ladies Chicago community!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for individuals who are interested in contributing to this blog. Whether you just want to write a single blog post or contribute regularly, we want to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re hoping to have two new posts each month on this blog. Blog posts could consist of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Event Recaps (either an R-Ladies Meetup or Study Group Meeting or another R-related event)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning something new in R (introducing a package or function in R)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member profiles (we would love to spotlight members of the R-Ladies Chicago Community)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details about contributing, please visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rladies-chicago/blog&#34;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please email us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:chicago@rladies.org&#34;&gt;chicago@rladies.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization</title>
      <link>/project/dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/dataviz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The data viz study group discusses different ways to visualize data in R. Activities that we&amp;rsquo;ve done include:&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; Taking on the monthly &lt;a href=&#34;http://reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;r/DataIsBeautiful&lt;/a&gt; challenge.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; Exploring functionalities of ggplot2&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; Visualizing specific data sets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://rladies-chicago.slack.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;slack&lt;/a&gt; channel &lt;strong&gt;#sg-dataviz&lt;/strong&gt; or email study group coordinator Ola [at] rladies dot org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrostatistics</title>
      <link>/project/astrostatistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/astrostatistics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>/project/nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/nlp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrostatistics in R: Predicting Solar Flares</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-08-27-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-08-27-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For our August meetup, the Astrostatistics Study Group (ASG) will talk about their ongoing project in predicting solar flares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R-Ladies board member and founder of the ASG, Caroline K. Williams will introduce the Astrostatistics study group and NASA Datanauts program she recently joined. She will also present the basic principles of Deep Learning that will be applied to the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh Goldberg, a member of the ASG will present on a topic in data science that is often overlooked or does not get much coverage but is required to move any project forward: data exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ASG adviser, Troy Hernandez will discuss how he got involved in the Solar Flare project as a mentor for the Space Weather Team of the 2017 NASA Frontier Development Lab. He will also talk about the progress of the analysis, and what he envisions for the ASG to achieve in this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to RSVP on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-chicago/events/253881898/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataCamp &amp; DataViz</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-05-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-05-meetup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Time! R in Minecraft with the &#39;miner&#39; package</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-07-19-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-07-19-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David Smith will talk about the &amp;lsquo;miner&amp;rsquo; package, how to set up your own Minecraft server, and how to use and extend the package. He&amp;rsquo;ll also provide a few examples of the package in action in a live Minecraft session! Fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The miner package is intended mainly for kids, to inspire them to learn R while playing Minecraft. But the development of the package also provides some useful insights into how to build an R package to interface with a persistent API, and how to instruct others on its use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This package is a collection of simple functions that allow you to connect with a Minecraft instance, manipulate the world within by creating blocks and controlling the player, and to detect events within the world and react accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About the speaker: David Smith is a developer advocate at Microsoft, with a focus on data science and the R community. He has been a long time facilitator and a good ally for R-Ladies Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP on the Meetup page and let us know if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Study Group Kick-Off Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-06-26_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-06-26_nlp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The NLP Study Group is starting their summer book club! Join us as we start discussing the first two chapters of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidytextmining.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Text Mining with R&lt;/a&gt;. All are welcome! Please email study group coordinator Katherine [at] rladies dot org with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Study Group Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-07-09_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-07-09_nlp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note this meeting has been rescheduled to &lt;strong&gt;6pm on Tuesday, July 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NLP Study Group is working through their summer book club! Join us as we start discussing the first two chapters of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidytextmining.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Text Mining with R&lt;/a&gt;. We will also have a lightning talk about the tm package. All are welcome! Please email study group coordinator Katherine [at] rladies dot org or join our &lt;strong&gt;#sg-nlp&lt;/strong&gt; slack channel with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Study Group Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-08-13_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-08-13_nlp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The NLP Study Group is working through their summer book club! Join us as we discuss the third chapter of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidytextmining.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Text Mining with R&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;tf-idf&lt;/strong&gt;. We will also have a lightning talk about a package related to working with text data. All are welcome! Please email study group coordinator Katherine [at] rladies dot org or join our &lt;strong&gt;#sg-nlp&lt;/strong&gt; slack channel with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Study Group Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-09-17_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-09-17_nlp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us as we discuss the fourth chapter of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidytextmining.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Text Mining with R&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;n-grams&lt;/strong&gt;. We will also have a lightning talk about a package related to working with text data. All are welcome! Please email study group coordinator Katherine [at] rladies dot org or join our &lt;strong&gt;#sg-nlp&lt;/strong&gt; slack channel with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Summer Social: Sip &amp; Code</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-07-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-07-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We will taste some wines (and non-alcoholic drinks too!) and rate them based on the winemag.com scoring system. Then, we will work together in small groups to analyze and visualize the wine preferences of R-Ladies in R! Wine is absolutely optional &amp;ndash;we&amp;rsquo;ll have non-alcoholic beverages &amp;amp; food too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll also be introducing some R-Ladies Chicago outreach initiatives, including our new website: rladieschicago.org and kicking-off our Random Acts of Coffee program!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be no formal technical talk at this meeting; rather, a time to network with fellow R-Ladies while doing a collaborative coding activity. This is part of our “social” Meetups, focused on networking and idea exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP on the Meetup page and let us know if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
