<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R-Ladies Chicago on R-Ladies Chicago</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R-Ladies Chicago on R-Ladies Chicago</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out R Tours</title>
      <link>/post/2018-09-rtours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-09-rtours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At R-Ladies, we want everyone to feel welcome, especially women and minority genders. Our favorite part of R-Ladies is cultivating an inclusive learning community–it is a challenge, but well worth it. As an R Community, where we are passionate about what we do in R, accessibility and inclusivity also means cultivating a welcoming environment for R users of all levels–from beginner to expert to everyone in between.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chicago organizing team works hard to plan our events intentionally where there is a combination of tutorials, talks about specific topics, and social events that showcase the strengths and address the interests of the local R-Ladies community. Some of these events will be better for beginners than others, but we hope that people will join us regardless of their R proficiency. We also hope our members will give us feedback on what they want to learn about in the future. In order to make our meetups more accessible, regardless of the topic, we’ll be piloting a new initiative: &lt;strong&gt;R Tours&lt;/strong&gt;! R Tours will be a 15-minute orientation on R essentials that immediately precede in person meetups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;why-tours&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Tours?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a couple events this past summer, a number of attendees said they had never even seen RStudio before or had just downloaded R on their computer before coming to the meetup. The purpose of R Tours is to provide a super-quick overview to complete beginners before (ideally, each) meetup. Somethings we are considering when developing this initiative:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do beginners need to get the most out of that day’s meetup? We’ll open RStudio and introduce each window. We’ll install and load any packages that are necessary for the talk. The goal is for beginners to know where to look when someone live codes. We also don’t want them to be discouraged from following along on their own computers because they had trouble installing things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This isn’t an in-depth tutorial or class that will provide all the information one needs. Also, we want attendees to download the script and run with it. So we used base R with no other packages or files necessary (other than what might be necessary for that day’s meetup). However, we will point attendees to resources where they can learn more about R!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hope that this will be a sustainable, recurring activity that we can do before every meetup to help beginners get more out of each meetup. We also hope it will facilitate community building within our R-Ladies Chapter, where other R-Ladies members can lead this 15-minute tour. It is a great opportunity to contribute to R-Ladies while practicing R teaching skills (and it’s not a big time commitment either!).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re including a draft of what our R tour might consist of. Check out this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rladies-chicago/beginners-r&#34;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;, where we’ll be updating our R tour for each meetup. This is still a work-in-progress and feedback is greatly appreciated! :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;an-example-of-an-r-tour&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;An Example of an R Tour&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;### R-Ladies Chicago R TOUR

# Load Data into workspace. Here, we&amp;#39;re loading a sample dataset that is already in R
data(&amp;quot;iris&amp;quot;) 

# See the first six rows of the dataset
head(iris) 

# See how large the dataset is
dim(iris) # output shows number of rows then number of columns

# What is this dataset about? You can use ? for other functions to get more info
?iris 

# See a subset of your data
# Show data where petal length is greater than 2 cm
subset(iris,iris$Petal.Length &amp;gt; 2)

# Save the data as a file in your working directory
write.csv(iris,file=&amp;quot;my_iris_data.csv&amp;quot;) 

# Read a file into R from your working directory
my_iris_data &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;quot;my_iris_data.csv&amp;quot;) 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Viz Study Group Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-09-10_dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-09-10_dataviz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Data Viz study group for their first meeting!  We&amp;rsquo;ll be exploring the grammar of graphics with R. There will also be an introduction to ggplot2. All are welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please email study group coordinator Ola [at] rladies dot org or join our &lt;strong&gt;#sg-dataviz&lt;/strong&gt; slack channel with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-chicago/events/254251305/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-chicago/events/254251305/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Blog Posts</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-16_blog_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-16_blog_info/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R-Ladies Chicago is excited to start this blog to showcase the perspectives of different members in the R-Ladies Chicago community!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking for individuals who are interested in contributing to this blog. Whether you just want to write a single blog post or contribute regularly, we want to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re hoping to have two new posts each month on this blog. Blog posts could consist of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Event Recaps (either an R-Ladies Meetup or Study Group Meeting or another R-related event)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning something new in R (introducing a package or function in R)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member profiles (we would love to spotlight members of the R-Ladies Chicago Community)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details about contributing, please visit our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rladies-chicago/blog&#34;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please email us at &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:chicago@rladies.org&#34;&gt;chicago@rladies.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization</title>
      <link>/project/dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/dataviz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The data viz study group discusses different ways to visualize data in R. Activities that we&amp;rsquo;ve done include:&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; Taking on the monthly &lt;a href=&#34;http://reddit.com/r/dataisbeautiful&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;r/DataIsBeautiful&lt;/a&gt; challenge.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; Exploring functionalities of ggplot2&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; Visualizing specific data sets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://rladies-chicago.slack.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;slack&lt;/a&gt; channel &lt;strong&gt;#sg-dataviz&lt;/strong&gt; or email study group coordinator Ola [at] rladies dot org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrostatistics</title>
      <link>/project/astrostatistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/astrostatistics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Language Processing</title>
      <link>/project/nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/nlp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;Git&#39; down with Git &#43; R (Workshop &amp; Tutorial)</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-11-13-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-11-13-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about using Git &amp;amp; R at our November Meetup! R-Ladies Board Member Ola Giwa will lead a tutorial and workshop to get you up and running with Github and using Git in your workflow. This session will discuss:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Version control and why it is important&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fundamental git commands&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Github for collaboration!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is extremely beginner-friendly! We encourage anyone, regardless of R &amp;amp; Git/Github proficiency, to join us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-chicago/events/255727048/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astrostatistics in R: Predicting Solar Flares</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-08-27-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-08-27-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For our August meetup, the Astrostatistics Study Group (ASG) will talk about their ongoing project in predicting solar flares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;R-Ladies board member and founder of the ASG, Caroline K. Williams will introduce the Astrostatistics study group and NASA Datanauts program she recently joined. She will also present the basic principles of Deep Learning that will be applied to the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Josh Goldberg, a member of the ASG will present on a topic in data science that is often overlooked or does not get much coverage but is required to move any project forward: data exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ASG adviser, Troy Hernandez will discuss how he got involved in the Solar Flare project as a mentor for the Space Weather Team of the 2017 NASA Frontier Development Lab. He will also talk about the progress of the analysis, and what he envisions for the ASG to achieve in this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to RSVP on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-chicago/events/253881898/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataCamp &amp; DataViz</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-05-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-05-meetup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DecembeR Holiday Party &amp; Collaborative Planning</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-12-05-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-12-05-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join R-Ladies Chicago to celebrate the holidays! Socialize with fellow R-Ladies and help us plan for 2019!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BEFORE THE EVENT:&lt;/strong&gt; Please fill out our survey to provide feedback on our past and future R-Ladies Chicago programs. We are looking for as many Chicago-area R-Ladies as possible to fill out this survey, even if you cannot attend this Meetup or have not attended one in the past. We would love your input! &lt;strong&gt;See the survey here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://tinyurl.com/rladies-survey&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://tinyurl.com/rladies-survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What we&amp;rsquo;ll do:&lt;/strong&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss best practices for working with survey data of all forms (e.g. numerical, strings, closed set, open response, etc.) in R. Then, we&amp;rsquo;ll work together in small groups to analyze data from our End of the Year Survey in R. By the end of the Meetup, we hope to have developed a data-driven list of R-Ladies Chicago events &amp;amp; goals for 2019!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll also socialize with fellow R-Ladies over holiday-themed treats :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be no formal technical talk at this meeting; rather, this will be a time to network with fellow R-Ladies while doing a collaborative coding activity. This is part of our “social” Meetups, focused on networking and idea exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to RSVP on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-chicago/events/256428023/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Time! R in Minecraft with the &#39;miner&#39; package</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-07-19-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-07-19-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David Smith will talk about the &amp;lsquo;miner&amp;rsquo; package, how to set up your own Minecraft server, and how to use and extend the package. He&amp;rsquo;ll also provide a few examples of the package in action in a live Minecraft session! Fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The miner package is intended mainly for kids, to inspire them to learn R while playing Minecraft. But the development of the package also provides some useful insights into how to build an R package to interface with a persistent API, and how to instruct others on its use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This package is a collection of simple functions that allow you to connect with a Minecraft instance, manipulate the world within by creating blocks and controlling the player, and to detect events within the world and react accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About the speaker: David Smith is a developer advocate at Microsoft, with a focus on data science and the R community. He has been a long time facilitator and a good ally for R-Ladies Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP on the Meetup page and let us know if you have any questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HacktobeRfest at Haymarket Brewery!</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-10-16-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-10-16-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;R-Ladies Chicago and Chicago R User Group (CRUG) teamed up this month to bring you a joint meetup worth toasting to: HacktobeRfest at Haymarket Brewery! Listen to some beer-related talks and participate in our Beer Data Hack-a-thon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please RSVP on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/rladies-chicago/events/255245435/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Meetup page&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Study Group Kick-Off Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-06-26_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-06-26_nlp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The NLP Study Group is starting their summer book club! Join us as we start discussing the first two chapters of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidytextmining.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Text Mining with R&lt;/a&gt;. All are welcome! Please email study group coordinator Katherine [at] rladies dot org with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Study Group Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-07-09_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-07-09_nlp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note this meeting has been rescheduled to &lt;strong&gt;6pm on Tuesday, July 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NLP Study Group is working through their summer book club! Join us as we start discussing the first two chapters of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidytextmining.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Text Mining with R&lt;/a&gt;. We will also have a lightning talk about the tm package. All are welcome! Please email study group coordinator Katherine [at] rladies dot org or join our &lt;strong&gt;#sg-nlp&lt;/strong&gt; slack channel with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Study Group Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-08-13_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-08-13_nlp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The NLP Study Group is working through their summer book club! Join us as we discuss the third chapter of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidytextmining.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Text Mining with R&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;tf-idf&lt;/strong&gt;. We will also have a lightning talk about a package related to working with text data. All are welcome! Please email study group coordinator Katherine [at] rladies dot org or join our &lt;strong&gt;#sg-nlp&lt;/strong&gt; slack channel with any questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
