<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on R-Ladies Chicago</title>
    <link>/tags/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on R-Ladies Chicago</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a Dataset to R</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-21-mack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-21-mack/</guid>
      <description>The City of Chicago and Chicago Public Schools (CPS) have made data on annual enrollments, school locations, and other school features available to the public. After a bit of wrangling (frankly maybe more than just a bit) these data can be used in R to get key visualizations.
My own interest in the schools data began with a desire to understand more about the spread of charter schools in the city, and also more about the sharp enrollment declines that some regular public high schools have experienced since the early ’00s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Blog Posts</title>
      <link>/post/2018-07-16_blog_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-07-16_blog_info/</guid>
      <description>R-Ladies Chicago is excited to start this blog to showcase the perspectives of different members in the R-Ladies Chicago community!
We are looking for individuals who are interested in contributing to this blog. Whether you just want to write a single blog post or contribute regularly, we want to hear from you!
We’re hoping to have two new posts each month on this blog. Blog posts could consist of:
 Event Recaps (either an R-Ladies Meetup or Study Group Meeting or another R-related event)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>