<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on R-Ladies Chicago</title>
    <link>/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on R-Ladies Chicago</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Viz Study Group Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-09-10_dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-09-10_dataviz/</guid>
      <description>Join the Data Viz study group for their first meeting! We&amp;rsquo;ll be exploring the grammar of graphics with R. There will also be an introduction to ggplot2. All are welcome!
Please email study group coordinator Ola [at] rladies dot org or join our #sg-dataviz slack channel with any questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataCamp &amp; DataViz</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-05-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-05-meetup/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Time! R in Minecraft with the &#39;miner&#39; package</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-07-19-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-07-19-meetup/</guid>
      <description>David Smith will talk about the &amp;lsquo;miner&amp;rsquo; package, how to set up your own Minecraft server, and how to use and extend the package. He&amp;rsquo;ll also provide a few examples of the package in action in a live Minecraft session! Fun!
The miner package is intended mainly for kids, to inspire them to learn R while playing Minecraft. But the development of the package also provides some useful insights into how to build an R package to interface with a persistent API, and how to instruct others on its use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Study Group Kick-Off Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-06-26_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-06-26_nlp/</guid>
      <description>The NLP Study Group is starting their summer book club! Join us as we start discussing the first two chapters of Text Mining with R. All are welcome! Please email study group coordinator Katherine [at] rladies dot org with any questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Study Group Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-07-09_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-07-09_nlp/</guid>
      <description>Please note this meeting has been rescheduled to 6pm on Tuesday, July 10
The NLP Study Group is working through their summer book club! Join us as we start discussing the first two chapters of Text Mining with R. We will also have a lightning talk about the tm package. All are welcome! Please email study group coordinator Katherine [at] rladies dot org or join our #sg-nlp slack channel with any questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Study Group Meeting</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-08-13_nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-08-13_nlp/</guid>
      <description>The NLP Study Group is working through their summer book club! Join us as we discuss the third chapter of Text Mining with R on tf-idf. We will also have a lightning talk about a package related to working with text data. All are welcome! Please email study group coordinator Katherine [at] rladies dot org or join our #sg-nlp slack channel with any questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Chicago August Meetup</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-08-27-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-08-27-meetup/</guid>
      <description>More information coming soon!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Ladies Summer Social: Sip &amp; Code</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-07-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-07-meetup/</guid>
      <description>We will taste some wines (and non-alcoholic drinks too!) and rate them based on the winemag.com scoring system. Then, we will work together in small groups to analyze and visualize the wine preferences of R-Ladies in R! Wine is absolutely optional &amp;ndash;we&amp;rsquo;ll have non-alcoholic beverages &amp;amp; food too.
We&amp;rsquo;ll also be introducing some R-Ladies Chicago outreach initiatives, including our new website: rladieschicago.org and kicking-off our Random Acts of Coffee program!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>