<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meetups on R-Ladies Chicago</title>
    <link>/tags/meetups/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meetups on R-Ladies Chicago</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/meetups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing our 2020 Career Series!</title>
      <link>/post/2020-02-07-career-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-02-07-career-series/</guid>
      <description>R-Ladies Chicago is proud to host our three-part Career Series in February, March, and April. With hiring season on the horizon, our Career Series will empower R-Ladies with the skills necessary to succeed in the data field. Join us for any/all of these events!
Thank you to Groupon for hosting! All events will take place at Groupon Corporate Headquarters (600 W. Chicago Avenue; Chicago, IL 60654).
Please check in at the front desk then go up to the third floor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join Us!</title>
      <link>/project/join/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/join/</guid>
      <description>R-Ladies is a worldwide organization that promotes gender diversity in the R community via meetups and mentorship in a friendly and safe environment.
Join our Slack community at this link: https://rladiesinvite.herokuapp.com/
Follow our Meetup age and join us at our in-person events: https://www.meetup.com/rladies-chicago/
We are always looking for fellow R-Ladies who are interested in giving a talk, suggesting a Meetup topic, leading a study group, or writing a blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Us!</title>
      <link>/project/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/support/</guid>
      <description>We are always looking for organizations to support our monthly Meetups! Specifically, we look for companies or organizations that can host us in their space and/or provide food and drink for Meetup attendees.
If you are interested in potentially hosting R-Ladies, please fill out this Google Form. Also, please read our Sponsor Space Requirements &amp;amp; Guidelines for details about what a host space needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out R Tours</title>
      <link>/post/2018-09-rtours/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-09-rtours/</guid>
      <description>At R-Ladies, we want everyone to feel welcome, especially women and minority genders. Our favorite part of R-Ladies is cultivating an inclusive learning community–it is a challenge, but well worth it. As an R Community, where we are passionate about what we do in R, accessibility and inclusivity also means cultivating a welcoming environment for R users of all levels–from beginner to expert to everyone in between.
The Chicago organizing team works hard to plan our events intentionally where there is a combination of tutorials, talks about specific topics, and social events that showcase the strengths and address the interests of the local R-Ladies community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>